

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Thesis: 'Nonlinear Effect Mitigation in Optical Fiber Communication Systems Using Recurrent Neural Network'
- Introduced data generation and parallel programing to Big Data Analytics project resulting in increased speed and accuracy
- Built recommendation song application 'Dionysongs' that recommends songs based on text similarity.
- Won a competition with 4 firms to secure major project with Cadence Design System.

### SKILLS / CERTIFICATIONS

- Python
- MatLab
- C/C++
- Java
- Data Analytics and Engineering
- Apache Spark
- SQL / NoSQL Database
- Data Wrangling with MongoDB
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect
- Docker
- · Al and Machine Learning
- Git
- Jira
- CCNA, CCNP Routing and Switching
- CCNA Security

#### **BUSINESS SKILLS**

- Project management
- Persuasive communication
- · Facilitation and mentoring
- Teamwork and collaboration

#### **LANGUAGES**

- Arabic (Native)
- English (Fluent)

## **REFEREES**

Available Upon Request

# **IBRAHEEM TAHA**

| ibraheemtaha@yahoo.com | | +30 (0) 6946362400 | Athens, Greece | | linkedin.com/in/ibraheemtaha/ |

My passion for continuous learning, including completion of a dual Masters in Big Data and 5G, and ability to learn quickly have given me a detailed knowledge of data science and data engineering. Running my own IT academy has allowed me to develop others in this field and become both a strong leader and team player. I am experienced in effectively collaborating with multiple development teams to build data processing pipelines and cloud-based platforms. I have a proven ability to solve complex networking, data, and software programs.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### 2020 – 2020 | Machine Learning Intern | Orange Labs | France

Implemented smart non-linear equalizers for big data long-haul fiber optics transmission systems by:

- Data Engineering; Preparation, Optimization, and Processing, and Data Analysis.
- Best positioning AI and ML techniques for data non-linear effects mitigation.
- Introducing deep learning approaches to assist current research in the field.

#### 2017 - Current | Co-Founder and Instructor | HiTechA Academy | Palestine

Created a learning environment, and facilitated network and systems courses including Python, C++ and CCNA Routing and Switching.

# 2016 – 2018 | Design Verification and Product Validation Engineer | Cadence Design Systems | Palestine

Contributed to software development of the cutting edge Xcelium Parallel Simulator by:

- Writing verification environment scripts using Python, NLP, Bash, Linux and Git.
- Verifying design function using System Verilog simulators.

### 2015 - 2015 | NET Developer | Isra' Software & Computer | Palestine

Built websites using ASP, converting to C# classes and instigated automatic handling with connection to SQL database.

### **EDUCATION / PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT**

# 2022 – Current | Dual Ph.D.'s of Data Engineering | Interactive Exploration & Analytics on Complex Big Data

National and Kapodistrian University of Athens, Greece and Aalborg University, Denmark.

#### 2018 - 2020 | Dual Masters of Data Science | Big Data Analytics and 5G

National and Kapodistrian University of Athens, Greece and Télécom Paris, France.

#### 2011 - 2016 | Bachelor of Science | Computer Engineering

An-Najah National University. Nablus, Palestine.

# **2014 – 2015 | Erasmus Mundus Exchange Scholarship | Computer Science** Uppsala University, Uppsala, Sweden.

2012 – 2012 | Business and Government Leadership, Public Speaking, Cross Cultural Communication and Cultural Awareness Summer School | Business & Leadership Lancaster University, United Kingdom.